misco.co.uk 2017-06-06

# Security and Privacy Statement - Misco.co.uk

  * Homepage
  * Help Centre
  * Misco UK Limited Privacy Policy

## April 1, 2016

* * *

  * Personal Information Collected By Misco UK
  * Use of Information Collected By Us
  * Sharing of Information with Third Parties
  * Affiliate Programs
  * Security
  * Corrections/Information Removal/Opt-Out
  * Data Protection
  * Contact Information
  * Business Transfer
  * Limitations on Liability

* * *

By visiting the Misco UK website or any other websites operated by Misco UK or its affiliates (collectively, the "Site"), you agree to accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site. Each time you use the Site, you should check the date of this Privacy Policy (which appears above) and review any changes that have been made since your last visit to the Site. 

Throughout Misco UK’s years of operation, we have developed relationships with our customers based on respect and integrity. We're aware of the trust and confidence you demonstrate when you visit the Site and provide us with information. This Privacy Policy is posted to demonstrate our leadership in online security and customer service practices. We treat your information with the same honesty and sensitivity that we have displayed throughout our company's history. 

* * *

## 1\. Personal Information Collected By Misco UK

Misco UK uses information that we collect from our visitors and customers to improve your visit and shopping experience at the Site. For the purpose of the Data Protection Act (the Act), the data controller is Misco UK Limited of Caledonian Exchange, 19a Canning Street, Edinburgh EH3 8EG (We/Us). We gather the following types of information: 

### Information You Give to Us

We Collect Personal Information that is provided by Site users. "Personal Information" includes your name, address, telephone number, credit or debit card information, e-mail address, IP address. Personal Information is collected when you establish an account with us, place an order on the Site, or when you communicate with any of our departments such as customer service, sales or technical services through the Site, telephone, mail or fax. In some instances, we may obtain other people’s names and email addresses that you may choose to provide as part of our "email a friend" feature. 

### Tags

We (or service providers on our behalf) may collect information from visits to the Site through the use of "Tags." Tags are web page elements which may employ cookie technology that enable us to record data about visits to or transactions made on the Site. This information is sometimes known as "clickstream data." We may use this data to analyze trends and statistics to improve your online experience or our customer service. No Personal Information is collected through the use of Tags on the Site. 

### Cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and allows us to improve our site. 

This website uses the following types of cookies: session cookies, allowing us to “remember” content from page to page (these expire when you leave the website or close the browser); persistent cookies, which define the “Time To Live” and help us to determine your preferences (these will expire after the “Time To Live” period); and third party cookies, cookies from any other domain, such as recommended product and advertising services. Third-party cookies are covered by the third parties' privacy policy. Through the use of cookies, we may also collect and analyze the IP address used to connect your computer to the Internet; computer and connection information such as your browser type and version; operating system and platform; purchase history; confirmation when you open e-mail that we send you; and the URLs which lead you to and around the Site including the date and time. You can generally set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie. Software is also available from third parties which will allow you to visit the Site without providing this information. You are welcome to use the Site if you use such software but we will not be able to offer you our personalized services and we will be unable to accept any online orders from you.

For further information on cookies, please visit: [//www.misco.co.uk/help/cookie-policy](https://www.misco.co.uk/help/cookie-policy). 

### Orders

If you place an order through the Site, you will be required to provide contact, billing, and payment information. 

### Catalogue Requests and Email Newsletter Subscriptions

Upon placing an order through the Site, you may begin receiving both the Misco UK catalogue and the Misco UK email newsletter, based on the Personal Information you have provided, unless you opt-out of receiving such communications. If you request an email newsletter subscription, we will send you an email confirming your request. This confirmation process allows you to unsubscribe if you change your mind and decide not to join the list. Furthermore, the confirmation email will alert you if someone else has entered your email address into our email newsletter subscription list. In order to make our email newsletters more relevant and useful to you, our servers may receive a confirmation when you open an email message from Misco UK.

### Website Recording

The contract's content will be stored. You may store the terms and readily look them up. For safety reasons your order's data are not available via internet. We keep these data in confidence according to our privacy policy.

### Storage of concluded contracts

Our website may also use a website recording service which may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, page scrolling and any text keyed into website forms. Data collected by this service is used to improve our website usability. The information collected is stored and is used for aggregated and statistical reporting, and is not shared with anybody else.

* * *

## 2\. Use of Information Collected By Us

We use this information in an effort to improve your experience on the Site, to provide services to you and to communicate with you about information that you request. We may also use this information to help us target specific offers to you, to help us develop and improve our Site, and to tailor our Site to your interests. 

We may also contact you with relevant promotional material when you do not complete your purchase with us. You can opt out of this service at any time, by clicking on the unsubscribe link in any marketing email that you receive from us, or by sending an email to [cs@misco.co.uk](mailto:cs@misco.co.uk)

* * *

## 3\. Sharing of Information with Third Parties 

We will not rent, sell or otherwise disclose your Personal Information to unrelated third parties without your consent, except as stated in this Privacy Policy.

If you do not want to receive information from third parties you may opt out, by going to My Account > Update eDeal and Catalogue Preferences and un-ticking the relevant box. You may also email your request to [cs@misco.co.uk](mailto:cs@misco.co.uk).

### Service Providers

We may employ other companies or individuals to provide certain services to or on behalf of us such as analyzing customer lists and data, or performing marketing or consulting services. These third parties ("Service Providers") will only have access to the information needed to perform these limited functions on our behalf and are required to provide your Personal Information with at least the same level of protection and security as we use on the Site. Such Service Providers are prohibited from using your Personal Information for any purpose other than that for which such party was engaged by us and/or as stated in this Privacy Policy. Any Service Providers that use data received from us may only do so in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Credit Card Companies

If you place an order through the Site, the Personal Information you provide is transmitted to your credit card company to verify and authorize your purchase. At certain times we may offer financing options with or without third party participation. If you use a financing option, information provided by you (such as your address, birth date, social security number, and credit card number) may be used to request a credit report from third parties or may be sent to a third party for processing.  
Furthermore, we hereby inform you, in connection with your order, of the use of the "Fraud Expert" solution in addition to the processing of card not present payments. Your personal data is processed by Ingenico e-Commerce Solutions SPRL being the controller, for the purpose of preventing and combating fraud (determining risk levels associated with transactions, detecting and managing any resulting alerts, informing merchants to allow them to take decisions, "human" reviews of transactions with a specified level of risk, modelling of the score).

The collection of certain of your personal data is a mandatory requirement for this purpose. Without this data, your transaction could be delayed or rendered impossible and your order cancelled.  
This data is intended for the authorised departments of the Ingenico e-Commerce Solutions entities involved in such processing, and for the merchant, as well as for any third party whose involvement is required to ensure the smooth operation of the payment process and the functioning of the services offered.

### Third Party Partners

From time to time we might establish a business relationship with other third parties whom we believe are trustworthy. In such cases we might exchange, share and/or cross-reference information, including your name and postal mailing address, telephone number(s) and e-mail addresses that will enable such third parties to contact you regarding similar products and services that may be of interest to you. 

### Related Companies

We may share your postal and e-mail address, telephone number(s), customer preferences, and purchase history with our parent company Misco Luxembourg S.a.r.l. or its subsidiaries. We will never share any credit card information which you have given to us with any of these related companies.

### Aggregate Information

We provide aggregate information to some of our business partners. This information is used in a collective manner and does not identify you individually in any way. We collect and share aggregate information in order to know more about the general profile of our customers so that we can improve your shopping experience. 

### Carrier Partners

If you make a purchase through the Site, your name, telephone number and shipping information must be provided to third party shippers to deliver your purchase. There also may be instances in which we drop-ship orders directly to you from one of our manufacturers or suppliers. These drop-shippers are only given your name, postal address, and telephone number for the sole purpose of fulfilling your order.

### Third Party Transaction-Level Data

If you visit the Site from a third-party website the third-party website may be able to access select information from your individual transaction information. In order to track and credit your transaction the third-party website may give you a unique code, cookie or graphic which will uniquely identify you. This will only happen if you link directly from a third party website to the Site. Any transactions made at the Site while such a code is active will be reported back to the third party website. We will only report non-Personal Information to these websites such as the date of the transaction, the product(s) purchased and the amount spent. We will not report any information to these third party websites that will allow them to personally identify you. The presence of a third party navigation bar at the top of any page on the Site is an indication that the third party website may be able to see your activity on the Site. 

### Links to Third Party Site

The Site contains certain links to third party websites, such as our vendors. We are not responsible or liable for the privacy practices or content found on these websites. We recommend that you check the privacy policy of each website you visit. Links to third party websites are provided solely for your convenience and any submission of data to such websites shall be at your sole risk. 

### Law Enforcement and Protection of Users

To the extent permitted by law, we will disclose Personal Information to government authorities or third parties pursuant to a legal request, subpoena or other legal process. We may also use or disclose your information as permitted by law to perform charge verifications, report or collect debts owed, fight fraud or protect our rights or property as well as those of our affiliates, customers, or its users. You should be aware that, following disclosure to any third party, your Personal Information may be accessible by others to the extent permitted or required by applicable law. 

* * *

## 4\. Affiliate Programs

We maintain relationships with third party affiliate websites. Although we do not and cannot control the activities of the third parties that operate such websites, we will cease doing business with any affiliate that engages in abusive practices, including, for example, spam, trademark infringement, predatory means of attracting visitors, or unlawful activities. To report abuse by an affiliate, please contact our Affiliate Manager via email at [affiliate@misco.co.uk](mailto:affiliate@misco.co.uk). 

* * *

## 5\. Security

We employ 128-bit encryption technology in all areas of the Site which require you to provide your personal or account information, including those areas related to online ordering, order status, catalog request and contest forms. The Site utilizes industry-standard firewalls and Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to allow for the encryption of potentially sensitive Personal Information, such as your name, address and credit card number.

You should recognize, however, that no computer system is fully secure and that there are inherent risks associated with Internet transactions. To make sure you have the latest security features on your browser, you may want to download the most recent version of your favorite browser, which should have full SSL support. 

* * *

## 6\. Corrections/Information Removal/Opt-Out

If your name, e-mail or postal address, telephone number or other Personal Information changes, you may update, correct or omit the relevant information in “My Account”, by contacting us at listcleaning@misco.co.uk, or by sending a letter to: Misco, 10-14 Darby Close, Park Farm South Industrial Estate, Wellingborough, Northants, NN8 6XH. In addition, if you no longer wish to receive communications from us you may opt-out by emailing us at cs@misco.co.uk, sending a letter to: Misco, 10-14 Darby Close, Park Farm South Industrial Estate, Wellingborough, Northants, NN8 6XH or by clicking on the unsubscribe link within any marketing e-mail you receive from us. If you no longer wish to receive our catalogue please email [cs@misco.co.uk](mailto:cs@misco.co.uk). 

* * *

## 7\. Data Protection

Misco UK Limited is a Data Controller, as defined by the Data Protection Act (1998) (“the Act”). Our registration number is Z6290748. Data we hold is maintained in accordance with the Act, and we may contact you from time to time to verify and update this data.

You have the right to access the data we hold on you. We will supply this data within 40 days of a request being made, at a nominal charge of £10 per request. To request access to your data please write to us at Misco, 10-14 Darby Close, Park Farm South Industrial Estate, Wellingborough, Northants, NN8 6XH

You also have the right to request the correction or deletion of the data that we hold on you. Please contact [cs@misco.co.uk](mailto:cs@misco.co.uk) or write to us at Misco, 10-14 Darby Close, Park Farm South Industrial Estate, Wellingborough, Northants, NN8 6XH.

* * *

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please e-mail us at [cs@misco.co.uk](mailto:cs@misco.co.uk).

* * *

## 9\. Business Transfer

Misco UK Limited is a wholly owned subsidiary of Misco Luxembourg S.a.r.l.. However, in the event that Misco UK Limited is sold, has its assets acquired or transferred, whether voluntarily or involuntarily, or merges or becomes affiliated with any other division, individual or entity, any customer information owned or under the control of Misco UK Limited may be one of the transferred assets. We reserve the right, as part of such transaction, to transfer or assign the Personal Information and aggregate information we have collected from users of the Site.

* * *

## 10\. Limitations on Liability

IN NO EVENT WILL MISCO UK OR ITS PARENT, AFFILIATES, LICENSEES OR ANY PARTY INVOLVED IN CREATING, PRODUCING OR DELIVERING THE SITE OR ITS PRODUCTS OR SERVICES BE LIABLE IN ANY MANNER WHATSOEVER FOR ANY INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL, INDIRECT, SPECIAL OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF YOUR ACCESS, USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE SITE, OR IN CONNECTION WITH ANY FAILURE OR PERFORMANCE, ERROR, OMISSION, INTERRUPTION, DEFECT, DELAY IN OPERATION OR TRANSMISSION, COMPUTER VIRUS OR LINE OR SYSTEM FAILURE (INCLUDING LOSS OF PROFITS, LOSS OF BUSINESS OR DATA, BUSINESS INTERRUPTION, AND DAMAGES THAT RESULT FROM INACCURACY OF THE INFORMATION OR INCONVENIENCE, DELAY, OR LOSS OF THE USE OF THE SITE). THE FOREGOING LIMITATIONS APPLY WHETHER THE ALLEGED LIABILITY IS BASED ON CONTRACT, TORT, NEGLIGENCE, STRICT LIABILITY OR ANY OTHER BASIS, EVEN IF GLOBAL INDUSTRIAL OR ITS AFFILIATES OR ANY OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.
